today we're talking about uh dining
cryptographer networks sometimes it's
called dc nets
and the paper is called unconditional
sender and recipient
untraceability
um
so we're looking at a paper that
examines dc nets from 2012 by
herrerabalt
but really
um and i've i've sort of
done this myself um we're really looking
at the 1988 uh dining cryptographers
problem uh by the creator of both the
problem and the solution which is david
chow
um you can find the links to both papers
here or of course you can always find
them on the github
for the wasabi club
um so last week just to remind ourselves
what we were doing we talked about an
issue with coin joint implementations
um with respect to the resilient
reliance on a central coordinator
so removing the coordinator would
require some secure method of
participants declaring their anonymous
addresses
ideally anonymously so that other
participants can't de-anonymize them in
the coin joint
with coin shuffle we can replace the
coordinator with a shuffling of the
coins where each participant onion
encrypts their address with the public
keys of the latter participants they
then decrypt and shuffle all encrypted
addresses they ever see with their own
address and then hand off all the
encrypted addresses to the next
participant so essentially we talked
about creating this like shuffle mixnet
we talked about how it scales poorly
with many participants uh the more
participants you have more participants
need to be included and the more
participants in this link and if one
participant fails to
you know uh
shuffle and pass on the date information
then uh the entire thing fails and as a
side note electron cash which is the
bitcoin cash coin joint implementation
of coin shuffle
currently has this
uh uh working with five participants so
this gives you a sense about how well
this type of thing scales um
yeah um
so this is what we've been doing up
until now for next week we will decide
uh the paper at the end of this call and
everything is available on our github
okay so let's talk about the dining
cryptographers
um so what's the premise the premise is
that three cryptographers are sitting
down to dinner at their favorite three
star restaurants uh the waiter informs
them that arrangements have been made
with the maitre d uh for the hotel
uh
for the bill to be paid anonymously one
of the cryptographers might be paying
for the dinner or it might have been the
nisa
the three photographers respect each
other's right to making an anonymous
payment but they wonder if the nsa is
paying they resolve their uncertainty
fairly by carrying out the following
protocol
so just
being very clear here there are three
cryptographers at dinner
the participants are all trustworthy
these cryptographers all trust each
other and they're acting in in
as honestly as they can towards each
other and towards the protocol the
participants want to be able to tell if
someone in the group paid so if someone
paid they would like to be able to
reveal that but they don't want to out
the payer because that person deserves
the right to be able to pay anonymously
so we essentially want to know this
information we don't want anyone to
reveal if it was them
uh so let's visualize this so here we
have three cryptographers at a dinner
table
um
what we're going to do this is the
solution uh the protocol that trump uh
explains in his 1988 paper he says uh
you know orange is going to turn to his
right and he's going to put up a menu so
that green can't see and he's going to
flip a coin to get a uh essentially a
one or a zero shared secret between
himself and uh and pink
and then pink is going to open his menu
and in a very covert way uh flip a coin
between him him and in green and create
a shared secret in this case the zero
might be heads and the one might be
tails for example
and lastly green is going to turn to
orange flip a coin and write down a
shared secret
so uh these numbers are only known
between the two individuals on that side
of the table
uh so
um you know green is unaware of the
number between orange and pink
uh
okay and so what they're going to do is
each participant themselves is going to
xor
the value uh an exclusive or just means
that if you have the same number
uh you write zero so if you have one and
one that's a zero zero zero that's a one
or that's a zero as well but if you have
different numbers like a one and a zero
or a zero and a one then you simply have
the number one
uh so every individual is going to take
their two numbers and they're going to
xor
those numbers
uh in their own heads
so in this case we have you know orange
has a one and a one that's zero
uh
green has a one and a zero that's a one
and then pink has a one and a zero and
that's that's one
and
yeah yeah we can absolutely play it so
we can play it right now in real time
um
by taking the participants in this chat
and firstly we have to decide on an
order so uh adam do you want to just
call out the names in order
and uh and get them to do a shared
secret
well the very first thing is that
i'm going to be the waiter right because
someone has to decide who is paying
right
so
i will send someone a message
in private that he's play he's paying
okay
i'm the waiter i came here and i tell
you guys that hey guys your
your bill has been paid
now
you want to figure out if it's one of
you or the nsa
excellent so
what we'll do is we first need everyone
to remember and share in secret we're
going to do this
in public um which is not secure but uh
but just remember your shared secret so
what we're going to do is we're going to
start with uh
igor and lucas
and just
i guess uh
who wants to announce the numbers
wait igor has to tell his secret to
lucas
lucas has to tell his secret to raphael
you raphael has to tell his secret to
you one
and you all has to tell his secret to
you aviv
okay
so the
communication the secure communication
channel in this case is that
don't remember other people's secret
only the secret that's been told to you
so
igor
so i'm just saying the number right zero
one right okay zero
all right you look as you remember that
now say your secret to rafael
oh sorry zero
okay
raphael
remember that and say your secret to you
all right uh one
all right
people remember that and say your secret
to
there is
uh no
don't you exclusive or your secret
secret
that's right so you you want to just
take
the secret of that you have between you
and the person to your left and the
person to your right
uh so igor
um
you only care about your secret with
lucas and your secret with me
because that's where we are in the
circle yeah yeah i understand
so whoever i sent the message that he
paid he has to negate
his result
so let's start over igor
one
lucas
the xor is zero
rafael
and the xor was one
the first one
and
the xor is
um
one
all right so we have the xors
and
yeah you can go
so what's the accent
so that that's a four which is even
which means that no one paid
because i didn't send the message
[Laughter]
all right so i hope we learned something
from this
[Laughter]
[Music]
yeah no problem
okay so
uh
you know
what just happened is all all
participants
in the circle right the circle can have
as many participants as you want but the
rule is you look to your left to your
right and you establish a single secret
and in this case we're going to take a
one bit secret
so we already did that
took our one bit secret
and then every individual has to xor
that right so if it's a one zero that's
a one if it's
two zeros it's a zero if it's two ones
it's a zero x or just means exclusive or
so it means
either this or that but not both
um that's all that xor is another way of
thinking about xor
is thinking if the numbers are different
if you have a different number on your
left than on your right your xor value
is one if it's the same number it's zero
okay so now every individual knows their
own xor
right they can now state their export
uh
in the public message right so this is
step two phase two is the public message
in this case green says one orange is
zero uh pink says one
and what we do is we sum up all of the
numbers that we get we sum them all up
and in this case everyone gets the same
result which is two
if the if the sum is even
right
it means that nobody said anything
so in this case because nobody said
anything we know the nsa is the one that
paid it wasn't one of the members
sitting at the table because no one said
anything
right so that that is the protocol
now suppose that orange did in fact pay
for the dinner
well in this case orange is going to say
one
if you look at oranges secrets orange
has a one and a one which means the xor
should be a zero but orange isn't going
to say as zero orange is going to negate
that to say one
so now all three participants are going
to say what they have
and they're gonna add up all the results
which is one plus one plus one is three
and they're gonna get
the result that someone
uh
uh paid someone at the table paid
now you might think to yourself well
wait a second um hey sorry can someone
mute themselves it's it's getting a very
low
lucas i think that's you
lucas
sorry sorry
it's very loud
oh sorry sorry sorry
oh that's nice
okay
um yes uh so
um so why does this work
why does this work well let's take pink
as an example so just pretend like you
are pink and this is all you know about
the network what you know is that you
have a shared secret with green and you
have a shared secret with orange and you
know this the shared secrets
and uh and then you say uh uh in public
your xor which is one
and your your uh your pink you didn't
pay and now you're thinking to yourself
can i figure out if orange or
uh green paid well suppose you think
orange paid right if orange paid it
means that orange has a one with with
green that's their shared secret
however if you think green paid it means
that uh green has a zero
with orange now the problem is that you
don't know that information
and whether orange or green paid is
entirely based on whether that number
between them is a zero or a one
so
the the what what orange and green are
saying reveals nothing about whether
either of them paid or not
um so all you know is the sum of the
messages you heard was odd and so that
means that someone paid
and that's fundamentally what what wha
what's going on and you don't know if it
was alex or bob in this case orange or
green
so why is it always even this is
actually an interesting question why is
it always even well i want you to
imagine uh instead of a circle a line
you know orange um
purple green back to orange right
uh
the shared secrets between participants
if it changes if it goes from zero to
one
then the participant that experiences
that change in this case it's pink
essentially has a value of one
but if it stays the same as is the case
with with green like it's a flat line
above green
then it's a zero
um so if you notice something
interesting because it can only
oscillate between zero and one and it's
a circle it must always have an even
number of increasing times and
decreasing times
so it can never have an odd number
because it's a circle right so if it
started at one and then it goes down and
then it goes up and then it goes down
then it goes back up has to end at the
same place then it will always be an
even number and it doesn't matter
um how many so for example if all the
numbers were the same
like the number one then there would be
a zero uh total sum that's also even
um but even if you add more participants
and you have all sorts of clever ways to
separate the numbers the number of downs
and ups is always in total and even
number in this case four it's gone down
twice and up twice because it has to end
in the same place
so just a quick summary of the protocol
phase one we have a one bit secret that
must be shared between each participant
and their two neighbors regardless of
any participants there are
phase two is each participant must xor
their two shared secrets and then
broadcast the resulting one bit message
and then two prime is if you are the
payer or if you want to send a message
simply flip the result of the xor and
broadcast the resulting one bit message
and then phase three is that given all
of the messages that we've just heard we
collect all of them
and we stumb them and if the sum is even
the message is zero if it's odd the
message is one
okay um so i'm going to just stop for a
second and just ask is
unclear about at least the one bit
protocol for
dc net
is anyone unclear
any questions
it is clear for me
okay
great so we're going to move a little
bit we're going to move forward
um so we can generalize
uh dc networks with this xor symbol so
essentially what this is saying is that
um the message for any number of bits
for any k participants
is uh is essentially the xor of all
their participants messages
which and each participant's exor is the
xor of the
secret on the left the secret on the
right and the message they have
themselves they xor all of those
together and that's xor with everyone
else's
the final result is the message
from
uh from some participant
um in total
um okay
so now i want to show a quick example
uh of
how this would work with um
this work more visually
so i'm going to share screen
okay can everyone see this uh this setup
here
yes
okay so on
i'm gonna reenact this entire protocol
with
essentially a logic circuit simulator
and you can see the three phases up at
the top don't worry about the bottom the
first is the shared secret the second is
broadcast message and the third is
interpret group message
so starting from the left
um starting from the left uh what i have
here is just a random number generator i
click this little clock button
and it lets me create new shared secrets
so uh
in this case we have a secret between a
and b
is uh is a one because that's that's
bright green and then the secret between
b and c is a zero and the secret between
c and a is a is is a one
now over here i'm going to have the
broadcast message
component right so right now neither a b
nor c none of them are saying anything
but the result is that uh b and c both
have uh positive messages
both have a one message
and if we look at the far right
to interpret the group message i just
have this uh last little uh logical
circuit setup
and you can see that no cryptographer
has paid given what these uh
individuals have said
um so now i'm going to show you just by
clicking if b changes the message in
this case
looks like this then you can see that um
we get an odd number of um
uh of of red lights
and uh the result is that uh we have a
one at the far right so um
a cartographer has paid
um
yeah and now i'm going to turn on the
clock and what the clock is essentially
going to do is it's going to start
rounds
and so each round you can see
there there are new shared secrets and
therefore uh new setups between a b and
c
so you can see here even as many rounds
happen
uh the message at the end here is the
same no cryptographer has paid
now if i click on this message over here
on behalf of c
um
now we can see on the right it says a
cryptographer has paid
uh bright green but if you if you just
focus your eyes on the red dots
it's not clear that c is the pair
because the lights flicker
just as they did before kind of randomly
this is this kind of making sense to
anyone did anyone get anything out of
this because i it might be a bit much
um
okay
it's uh
if if you understand these gates then
you can make sense everyone learns it in
university then forgets it of course
but yeah
okay awesome so uh the one last thing i
wanted to show before we we end this
this uh
powerpoint is just uh
is just maybe this is uh too much
but uh okay
um so i have the same thing set up here
um yeah i know it can feel like a lot um
but uh
essentially uh over here to the right is
an output it's essentially like um
like a board um
which lets you type letters in and over
here we have five participants this time
and they have us eight bit message this
time not a one bit message what we're
gonna do is we're gonna pick a random
individual for example over here b
and uh you can see that the rounds are
happening very quickly and all the time
if i start typing
um i paid for
dinner
you will see it appear on the far right
over
here um but uh if you just focus your
eyes on the red dots then you can't tell
um who paid so i can type over here i
paid for dinner
[Music]
okay
anyways uh that's pretty much it you can
download logisim for free and you can
copy my um
you can copy my
um
project and uh and try for yourself okay
so let's finish this then
uh can you explain what the
correspondence is between the eight bit
number and the text message
say again
the i don't understand the corresponding
text that you typed and the
result
okay a great question you've all so the
point was
um
the point was that uh
[Music]
uh when i was typing i was typing on
behalf of one of the five participants
right pretending to be one of the five
participants that actually had something
to say to the rest of the group
um
but all of the participants are
constantly engaging in these rounds
where they get this 8-bit secret between
their their neighbors
and they keep publishing messages except
everyone is publishing blank messages
because no one has anything to say
so as i'm typing what's happening in
real time
is the rounds are happening many many
very quickly that's why the flashing
lights are flashing and the output is
what the group
message is the the
the the final message as xored by the
entire group
so is it like one bite of the message at
a time
exactly it's one bite at a time we get
we we get a one byte
uh secret anonymous group message sent
to all participants
because all participants engaged with
one byte
of of the protocol instead of
broadcasting then you just get a string
of zero bytes right
exactly
right and if you wanted to for example
broadcast the number you know 10 which
is one zero one zero in binary right you
would broadcast zero zero zero zero one
zero one zero so
it's still the case that most of the
protocol is empty
except for those two one bits
and their respective locations and so
the net result is a byte um with the
number 10.
thanks that makes sense
okay great so now uh we're gonna talk
about the issues so um i had a lot of
fun learning about dc nets and i spent a
long time just i really enjoyed reading
all the different papers um
uh the sad news is is that no matter how
cool or fun they are they're very
impractical
so we're gonna talk about why they're
practical the first is that they demand
a lot of bandwidth
so for starters if you want to say a
message
to
uh
in your group
then uh if your message is for example
one megabyte and there are n
participants let's say 10 then it
requires all of your peers to also
message a one megabyte
blank message
that is xored to your message so the
more participants there are the more
needless bandwidth is being wasted
right also it could be the case that
you have rounds where no one has
anything to say in that case you have an
empty message but it still costs
uh m times n
in size
um there's also really really critical
flaw which is that only one participant
is allowed to message the group per
round
so
there's it's actually not entirely true
that only one group uh one participant
is allowed to message per round the more
accurate thing to say is that for any
bit for any like byte or bit or whatever
in the protocol only one participant can
fill that bit with a message
um if you have two participants speaking
at the same time uh the round actually
collapses in on itself and so you start
to negate the message of one person with
the message of the other
and so for this reason it's actually
quite trivial to break a dc net so in
order to break a decent net all you need
to do
is not be not cooperate
either talk all the time or uh not
properly message your xor or do any of
the other potential things and then you
will uh successfully uh break the um
the dc net um
so yeah uh that's pretty much it i
didn't want to take too much time leave
it up to um
yeah so by following a strict protocol
of three phases per round we can
establish truly anonymous communication
for any of the participants so long as
their shared secrets remain secret
benefits we could use dc nets for
quantum participants who want to
anonymously broadcast their outputs to
the group and the downsides is a very
fragile system easily broken by
relationship participants that's also
quite a bit slower
um
yeah so i'll just leave it at uh with
one thing
uh suppose wasabi wanted uh our
participants to um
to uh do a dc net for their own uh
addresses right
so suppose we have you know 10 wasabi
wallet users
they want to do a dc net and push
their addresses one clever thing we can
do to deal with the problem of two
individuals interrupting each other is
by having a very large
round with a very large amount of data
like for example one megabyte
and have uh each participant take the
one megabyte um and create two one
megabyte shared secrets with the
adjacent participants
um and by the way shared secrets are
easily uh created with diffie-hellman
key exchange if we're using public key
cryptography
and
and essentially have users input their
address somewhere in the one megabyte
block
but
such that all the participants could fit
and that ideally uh no two participants
would overlap each other but i think
there's some definite definitely some
challenges there um
yeah anyways that's pretty much it i
think for me
thank you aviv
so i couldn't
get the outdoors to come here
actually
there is one altar and i couldn't
find his contact because it wasn't on
the paper
uh i i sent an email to charm too uh he
did not reply
so anyway uh
i couldn't get out or but i would have
one fun question for the author and
please if you know the answer then then
then say it so the paper says
perfect security is often realized using
some physical means
such as flipping a coin behind the menu
card
or more seriously personally handing
over a hard drive disc containing key
bits
and my question is
is this really often being realized in
practice
so
are people doing that
the hard drive this stuff
the hard drive this
is containing
for this protocol no
no yes i i really don't think so i don't
know the answer i don't think so
however i think that the
i don't remember the the paper because i
i read it a long time ago but
the problem i think is the how to get a
long enough key
because if you want to share for example
um a movie uh four
gigabytes
file for example then you need a four
gigabyte
key
right
so
how to
get that
uh yes you can have a hard drive
with
a a
long enough key
but you can also derivate
i mean
deterministically
from one not so big key
to a one really really long
so
in my opinion the the length of the key
is not
it's not really a problem in fact we are
at all our derivation schemes
for
private and public keys in bitcoins
in the bitcoin ecosystem are using
key derivation functions
for very small keys right so
i think it's not the problem
that's exactly actually this is one of
my discussion topic because this uh
this gave me an idea about wasabi that
yes this is what they are saying in the
paper that
we claim that if we initially exchange
key generators rather than continually
exchanging the keys itself the network
only requires a linear amount of
bandwidth in and
yeah so so exactly what you just said
it's in the paper so
this is really interesting because it is
similar to hd wallets right that's what
he said
and it could be directly applied to
wasabi too because you know in wasabi
with the synchronized request we are
actually
uh
sending
keys all the time with the synchronized
request right because there is the
there are two
two attacks there somehow uh why we
needed to do that but
it's actually not needed we could just
use this key generation
hd wallets and we could
we could
we could save a lot of bandwidth uh for
ourselves to
i'm not uh suggesting to start working
on it but uh i think that could work and
that would be awesome
yes i agree i didn't think about that
but yes it makes sense
i i would like to
to share
my my it's not my thought it's just
how this can be used in a
small different way
but i don't know if i can share my
screen
can i
i mean
okay
okay let me see yes i think everything
is okay
okay i will share my screen porn
okay
okay allow
let me know if you can see my screen
yes
okay
imagine
e is
igor
messaging
key
right let's call it
that
this is aviv
yes it has another random
i don't know
this is me
with another
another key
it's very small but they can be
as long as as needed right
so now someone that we don't know who
uh of course
we all know
the igor ki
the aviv ki and mikey
we all know that so
if you receive a message for example
someone
igor aviv or me
wants to send this message
to you for example or
or
yes for example to you adam
right
so
what we do is the encrypted message
let's call it encrypted message
will be
the message right
with
xor the keys
of wheat
right
this is an encrypted message
what you can do
then
is
decrypt the message the scripting
message will be the encrypted message
right
but
the the order is is not important
right because it's an xor
yes so you have the
the decrypt oh yeah wait wait
the decrypted method oh wow
the cryptid message
that is one two three four
so
you get the message that you really
don't know who sent you that message
right
so
this is something that can be used for
communication
the only problem we have is the ip
address
but if we can
hide the ip address in some way
for example some operating systems allow
you to
to
change
the ip address in in
in udp
packages right so
you really don't know i mean put a fake
id for example right
so you can send messages in this way
and you really don't know who sent the
message
so this is something that
basically
can be used
and
i don't know if this is useful
doesn't make sense
[Music]
i think this is the the the the most
important
application
i will stop
sharing all right
so
thank you anyone has anything to add to
that
uh one thing we haven't really discussed
but i think is really relevant for the
like the
context of um coin joints is uh how do
you establish the secure channels
between the peers um
it's related to that
i mean it's the same passage as the the
physical uh device part in the
paper
um
is the assumption that you use the prior
utx dose
to
do a key agreement
over those and like you authenticate the
other participants
um based on the coins that they
registered into mix
[Music]
sorry i changed my headphone and
sorry
okay
it's uh sorry well i
i understand your
your problem which is how do you
how do you bootstrap the system right
which which this
how do you in generally how do you
bootstrap a peer-to-peer network
but
but this paper was not uh
not talking about that
go ahead if i misunderstand something
no that that that's exactly it like um i
haven't yet read the coin shuffle plus
plus paper so
um
i was just
wondering indeed how do you bootstrap
and is the the general approach
uh to use the utxos going into the mix
in order to authenticate the
participants
yes the quench of a plus plus paper is
going to be next week and
if i remember well it does not talk
about that
it just talks about that as it is a
general problem a peer-to-peer network
is already given now this is what we can
do on the peer-to-peer network
so it doesn't uh talks about
bootstrapping
but yeah it's it's not an easy problem
because think about bitcoin core maybe
the most peer-to-peer network ever and
what do we do with bitcoin core we are
connecting to some core developers at
the very first start
those
those nodes
the address of their nodes are hard
coded into bitcoin core and that's how
you are bootstrapping it and what did
you do before
uh you were
you were
in in satoshi's time you were going to
the an irc server and
that's how you bootstrap bootstrap to
your bitcoin core
so
based on that bitcoin core is
using a centralized way to
semi-centralized way to bootstrap i
would say
there is probably no good solution for
that
i mean
the solutions are practical and good but
there is no idea solution maybe
well so in bitcoin specifically there's
you know uh the criticism against uh bip
151 where you can't really authenticate
the other peers so
um but i don't think it's the same
because in this context uh every
member
specifically in the context of using
these protocols for mixing coins
uh since people come in with utxos if
they expose the public key for that new
um
that's um like some sort of identity
anchor
um
so
to me it doesn't seem like an unsolvable
problem specifically in this context um
because it's only a communication about
a particular set of coins
um also your your question is not about
how do the peers find each other
um not in general it is but um
i mean
it depends what you mean by fine but uh
specifically i'm concerned about um
so
in the paper the the secrecy
um
basically falls apart if you have an
adversary that can eavesdrop uh on
everything
right because it can just see which one
of the participants like if it sees both
secrets of every participant then it can
basically see whether or not their
message was one or zero
um so you need to have a secure channel
to your um your left and right um
neighbors
yes that's correct
and uh again that there's no nothing
discussed about how to bootstrap that um
apart from you know physical drives and
stuff but
specifically in the context of of
bitcoin mixing um i i was wondering um
if uh the the utxos going into the mix
can be used as uh identifiers where you
can basically do uh kind of like stealth
addresses
uh like diffie-hellman key agreement on
the public keys of those udxos
in order to like
establish the other participants
identities
yeah possibly
i guess
but you know like this this protocol
that we talked about is so flawed in
from so many point of view that
you have to fix a lot of things
like the honesty problem
you have to fix a lot of things and i
think only after then you can think
about
how to
how to exchange keys
in a secure channel with each other
because that would that would
depend on the final
scheme
all right i
i have a bigger topic regarding the
paper which was not mentioned but it was
a large
large part of the paper and
and when he analyzed
autox against anonymity
did anyone who who thinks here who
understand the attacks against anonymity
section
pretty well who understood it
okay it was
probably the most difficult
part of it so
here is my
my conclusion
so
the anonymity set is n
all the participants of the protocol
that's an
unless an auto care participates
in this case the anonymity set of honest
participants is n minus 1.
so far it's clear
n is the number of participants n minus
one
is the anonymity that if annotation
participates
however if the attacker participates
with multiple participants
things become more interesting
in this case
the anonymity set of honest participants
is the honest component of the graph
graph
so this is what the paper says
what does this mean so for example if
the attacker controls the keys of both
neighbor of a participant
then the participants anonymity set
against the attacker is one
p had been the participants had been cbl
attacked
right it's it's understandable
and yes
and and and next however if the graph is
fully connected
then the attacker can only reduce the
anonymity set
by one now last week
we talked about
queen chapel and
i had the misunderstanding of coin
shafter that
the the graph is fully connected
but
you guys were like
no you can uh
pass messages to
so you guys were talking about the
circular graph and i was talking about a
fully connected graph
and i think this uh
this is the same scenario that
that in in aviv's explanation the
circular nature of quench of
uh i think
or yeah this is my question does this
apply to coin shafter
that
if the participants
if an autocad participates with multiple
participants
then
the
anonymity set of the honest participants
is the honest component of the graph
does this apply to coin shafter
that's that's my question
i think coin shuffle is more secure is
my intuition in that if
so if only one
participant
is tasked with
shuffling
um
and they decide to do it
wrong
yeah i'm not entirely sure
all right so wishful thinking fails us
we are not gonna find answer to this
question
but it would be interesting
anyway uh
i have
one last small thing that the paper says
we will leave the question of why this
is an unobservable anonymity system to
the reader and instead obtain a basic
generalization of the restaurant
protocol before moving on to attacks
so why is this an unobservable
anonymity system
anyone
because it's it uses the
principle of xor like
the fact that all you know about the
entire system is that there must be an
even number of
of uh ups and downs so to speak of
differences
and if you get an odd number you don't
know where
who it was the person that caused that
problem there's no nothing is revealed
and what would the unobservability mean
that the
messages given by the individuals
um
are
don't give any
insight in terms of whether what the
individuals themselves wanted to say
whether they want to say something or
nothing
that's what's bad so if
if we have a protocol
like the tor network where you are
ups
you you are observing all the tor
network messages that's an observable
anonymity system because it relies on
on the fact that
the
that there are honest communi there are
secure communications between some peers
but in this case
it doesn't matter everyone can broadcast
their messages to everyone
and whoever observes it cannot know
anything
that's the is that the point here
yeah
all right
i'm not sure i follow but
like the the way that the paper defines
unobservability
um
i mean it's pretty
pretty clearly defined it's just that
the messages are each message is
completely indistinguishable from random
noise
uh i think also to the participants not
just to uh like an adversary monitoring
the the network
yes exactly because the messages are
essentially an xor of of two random
[Music]
pieces of data right two shared secrets
that are
random so
um
yeah
so i'm not sure how like to compare this
to like onion routing because there's no
notion of broadcast there um
like each is sent just to a specific
peer
that is the point if you would be
i mean i think that is the point if you
would be able to observe all the
communication
between
that's being
broadcasted
to the network
actually i don't know
because you have to assume secular
communication in chinese
even here too
so what's the difference there you're
you're a good question
i i mean i i don't even
see how the
the definition applies
like i don't see how either
unlinkability or unobservability as
defined in the paper
uh really relates to the the onion
routing case where each message is
intended just for a single participant
uh like it's uh if if alice is uh trying
to talk to bob
via carol or something then she sends to
carol a single message that uh carol
then forwards to bob
um
but
that there's no like uh of course the
messages are linkable by carol because
alice sent them and and i mean you in
linkability by
uh having different messages
um so like carol can link alice's
messages to the message that she sent to
bob on alice's behalf
um but since there's no like
uh
like bob doesn't see alice's message to
carol he only sees carol's like message
to him
um i i don't see how the
like how it's
the the same notion the same property is
is um like how you can even examine it
in in the case of uh an in routing
yeah you've all is is right right so
here when it talks about unobservability
it says that
um you know actual messages sent from
the actors from from the participants
are indistinguishable from random noise
an unobservable system not only conceals
who is communicating with whom but also
hides which actor actually sent or
received messages in the face of a
passive global attacker
so uh tor isn't like that
right um you know for tor if you if you
send a message it's not hidden among
many other messages
you would have to do that you would have
to make sure that it's unobservable but
there's also nothing like you've all
said it's it's a completely different
system
so
um
yeah
okay that that was from me so whoever
i wasn't asserting anything i just um
like i didn't understand what how how
you
uh like no power if you if you wanna
explain more um
like uh it's just that i i didn't
understand what you meant not uh not
that i think that you're wrong
yeah because i was thinking out loud i i
so my initial thinking was that
the message that's being broadcasted in
dining cryptographers is the
is the
xors so whoever absol
observes that xors
it doesn't matter you cannot make any
conclusion out of that
but then i was saying that in tor the
message that's being broadcasted is the
actual communication between the many
parties in tor
so
observing that is
obviously dangerous
now but you pointed out that this is not
correct because
even in dining cryptographers there is
a private communication what's
but if you are observing it then you are
the anonymizing the whole system so
what i said first this is was my logic
it it was incorrect
but
then aviv came with that
i'm still not exactly sure how they
define an observability
this case but probably makes sense i
guess
is is that clear my point was that i
don't know the answer
yeah thanks
can can i ask uh
just one question like how practical
would it be
say if we if we did 10 megabytes of
of shared secrets between
uh to each two participants in a hundred
participant
group
how practical would that be
like suppose
right when
a coin joint is happening
um
uh we would have only one round
which would
have you know let's say 10 megabytes of
shared secret
lucas you were saying something
yes i think that that will what we were
talking about uh minutes ago i mean
the the length of the key
it it is not important because you can
generate a random key for i don't know
256 bits
yes for example with a difficult
key exchange
and then you can
use a key derivation function to
to create a key as long as you need i
mean the the the length of the key that
you need
so it's not that you have to share
all that
so real concern is that we we wouldn't
know and we can't stop a malicious
participant from from ruining
the process right
yeah i was also having a question about
that what incentivizes uh people to or
decent devices people to
be malicious and just
broadcast that
wrong number
in their xor round or something like
that
well it's the same that
uh motivates any malicious actor in a
cryptographic network it's it's that
they have an incentive for something not
to work right so in this case it would
be someone who has an incentive for
secure payments not to work
well to be fair the paper did not talk
much about that
if at all it was mostly assuming that
everything everyone is
honest
so
yeah but but again let me reiterate we
are preparing for queen shuffle plus
plus
so
hopefully
now we have a lot of questions and
questions
for us
okay i'm very much looking forward to it
yeah me too because i i liked the idea
of this but i was just thinking about
this problem
also i i i should point out that there
are no mainstream
use cases for dc nets so you if you if
you go around and try to find
active
um
like applications that use dc nets you
you can't find them today
and very likely due to their narrow use
of applications and also the fact they
have these problems
well
every every anonymity network come out
of that right tor
i2p
swings what is the lightning network
used
what has dandelion
coins of plus plus
these are all based on this dc network
research
or this is the root of it
by the way there is a new guy on the
block that is the locking net
it's an invention of
one of the monero
monero
guys
yes they have a
it's a mix
between something like a new new
new age store
and
i2p
uh
that looks interesting too they allow
communication using udp too
and
it's
it is interesting i don't know it works
let me write here is
lucky
net
um
it works i was playing with that
and it works
um
just to have in mind
yeah that's interesting another thing
that came out recently is the neem
network
you heard about it
that uh
i think even amir taki was involved with
it in at one point
all right what test topics you have
that's it for me
then let's move on then
and
the next
next
week we are obviously going to look into
coin shuffle plus plus
after that we are looking into cash
fusion which is the bitcoin cash guys
figure something out about an equal
amount
and
after that we agreed that we are going
to look into
papers those are trying to quantify
privacy
and
and aviv
found a great research
collection a bibliography of anonymity
research which is
freehaven.net
slash
on on
beep and
yeah there is like a bunch of research
it's it's it's it's really great
like a bunch of research meaning
thousands of anonymity research
okay
and
just a question
don't we want to rename the wasabi
research club to dining bitcoiners
[Music]
it would be fun but i'm too lazy to fix
all the links and stuff
all right guys
then
thank you for the
dinner
and thank you for the nfc that
paid our dinner
thank you
thank you guys